Efren Francisco Jose Palacios Puma

5552 Larch st. Vancouver, BC V6M 4E1

linkedin.com/in/franciscojosepalacios

(778) 869-5819 francis_pancho12@hotmail.com

PROFILE

A passionate, ambitious, hard-working and well-rounded Sociology and International Relations graduate who loves working to help others. I work very well in teams and have vast experience in leadership and collaboration as well as having high interpersonal and communication skills.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts - University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada

Completion:

April 2018

B.A. major in Sociology and minor in International Relations

International Baccalaureate Diploma - The American School of Quito, Quito, Ecuador

Completion: July 2013

International Baccalaureate Diploma, alongside high school diploma recognised in the United States and Ecuador.

ASSETS

Technical Skills

- HTM, CSS,
- Git, JSON
- Salesforce
- Zendesk

Languages

- Spanish (Native proficiency)
- English (Bilingual proficiency)
- Portuguese (Elementary proficiency)
- French (Elementary proficiency)

Academic Achievements

- Diploma award in recognition as one of the most outstanding students of the class of 2013 of the American School of Quito
- Ecuadorian government scholarship granted to study at UBC worth CAD 240,000
- Outstanding delegation award at the National Model United Nations in New York City March 2015, March 2016.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Peer Advisor – UBC Department of Sociology, Vancouver Canada

January 2018 – April 2018

 Responsible for advising upcoming and current sociology students, communicating available undergraduate opportunities, events, courses and career paths.

Community Coordinator – *UBC Recreation Nitobe Basketball League*, Vancouver Canada

April 2017 – April 2018

 In charge of ensuring that all participants in the Free-Agent System are properly informed about procedures for integration into the Leagues Program. Conduct supervision of games on a weekly basis to ensure everything operates perfectly.

Event Staff – UBC Athletics Department, Vancouver Canada April 2018

September 2016 –

· Responsible for set up and takedown of venues for the UBC Thunderbird games, as well as performing a variety of tasks including ticketing, on-site security, and ushering.

Director of Delegate Affairs – UBC Model United Nations (UBCMUN), Vancouver Canada March 2016 – January 2017

• Oversee and manage conference registration, recruitment, and external promotion of the 2017 UBCMUN conference, attracting about 300 students from universities in Canada and the United States.

Vice-President Logistics – UBC Model United Nations Student Association (MUNSA), Vancouver April 2015 – April 2016

• In charge of coordinating 5 domestic and international conference's logistics, including booking domestic and international flights, booking train and bus tickets, and hotel accommodations; as well as reserving UBC classroom space for MUNSA events.

Social Team Member – UBC International Student Association (ISA), Vancouver Canada September 2015 – April 2016

• Part of a group of international students in charge of organizing different events throughout the year, in order to bring together the international student community at UBC

Fundraising Volunteer – Shinerama (Students Fighting Cystic Fibrosis), Vancouver Canada

September 2013

• Led fundraising efforts to raise money to fund research that can seek a cure for Cystic Fibrosis in Canada.

Fundraising Volunteer– Habitat for Humanity Ecuador, Quito Ecuador

September 2012 – April 2013

• Assisted in all stages of realizing a project to build a house in a rural community in Ecuador, leading fundraising efforts to raise funds (personal goal of 1000 USD); via corporate donations and fundraisers, to build the house and assisting in its construction.

REFERENCES

Steph Mihalatos Manager, Varsity Events UBC Athletics
b. 604.822.0696 | c. 604.833.2235